 1. She looked down on Gopher Prairie. “The snow stretching without break from street to devouring prairie beyond”, wiped out the town’s pretence of being a shelter. “The houses” were “black specks on a white sheet”. “metaphor”
 2. And the “skirts”! What a sight were those skirts! “They were nothing but vast decorated pyramids”; on the summit of each was stuck the upper half of a princess. “metaphor”
 3. I was staring directly in front of me, at the back of the “driver’s neck”, which was a relief “map of boil scars”.“metaphor”
 4. She was handsome in a rather leonine way. Where “this girl was a lioness”, “the other was a panther — lithe and quick”. “metaphor”
 5. His “voice” was a “dagger of corroded brass”.“metaphor”
 6. Wisdom has reference only to the past. The “future” remains forever an “infinite field for mistakes”. You can’t know beforehand.“metaphor” 
 7. He felt the “first watery eggs of sweat” moistening the palms of his hands.“metaphor” 
 8. At the last moment before “the windy collapse of the day”, I myself took the road down.“metaphor” 
 9. The man stood there in the middle of the street with the “deserted dawnlit boulevard telescoping out” behind him.“metaphor”
10. Leaving Daniel to his fate, she was conscious of “joy springing in her heart”. “metaphor”
11. He smelled the ever-beautiful smell of “coffee imprisoned in the can”. “metaphor”
12. We talked and talked and talked, easily, sympathetically,” wedding her experience with my articulation”.“metaphor” 
13. We need you so much here. It’s a dear old “town”, but it’s a “rough diamond”, and we need you for the “polishing”, and we’re ever so humble....“metaphor” 
14. They walked along, “two continents of experience and feeling”, unable to communicate.“metaphor” 
15. ”Geneva, mother of the Red Cross, hostess of humanitarian congresses” for the civilizing of warfare! “metaphor”
16. She and the kids have filled his sister’s house and their “welcome is wearing thinner and thinner”. “metaphor”
17. ”Notre Dame squats in the dusk”.“metaphor”
18. I am the new year. I am an “unspoiled page in your book of time”. I am your next chance at the art of living.
I am your opportunity to practice what you have learned during the last twelve months about life.
All that you sought the past year and failed to find is hidden in me; I am waiting for you to search it out again and with more determination.
All the good that you tried to do for others and didn’t achieve last year is mine to grant — providing you have fewer selfish and conflicting desires.
In me lies the potential of all that you dreamed but didn’t dare to do, all that you hoped but did not perform, all you prayed for but did not yet experience. These dreams slumber lightly, waiting to be awakened by the touch of an enduring purpose. I am your opportunity.“metaphor” 
19.    Autumn comes 
And trees are shedding their leaves,
And “Mother Nature blushes” 
Before disrobing.“metaphor” 
20. He had hoped that Sally would laugh at this, and she did, and in a sudden mutual gush they cashed into “the silver of laughter” all the sad” secrets they could find in their pockets.“metaphor” 
21. All across the Union audiences clamour for her arrival, which will coincide with that of the new century. For we are at the fag-end,” the smouldering cigar-butt, of a nineteenth century” which is just about to be ground out in “the ashtray of history.” “metaphor”


1. He went about her room, after his introduction, looking at “her pictures, her bronzes and clays”, asking after the creator of this, the painter of that, where a third thing came from. 
 2. She wanted to have a lot of children, and she was glad that things were that way, that “the Church” approved. Then the little girl died. Nancy broke with Rome the day her baby died. It was a secret break, but “no Catholic breaks with Rome’ casually.“metonymy” 
 3. Evelyn Glasgow, get up out of that chair this minute. The girl looked up from her book. What’s the matter?
“Your satin”. “The skirt” ’ll be a mass of wrinkles in the back. “metonymy”
 4. Except for a lack of youth, “the guests” had no common theme, they seemed strangers among strangers; indeed, “each face”, on entering, had straggled to conceal dismay at seeing others there. “metonymy”
 5. She saw around her, clustered about the white tables, “multitudes of violently red lips, powdered cheeks, cold, hard eyes, self-possessed arrogant faces, and insolent bosoms”. “metonymy”
 6. ”Dinah”, a slim, fresh, “pale eighteen”, was pliant and yet fragile.“metonymy” 
 7. The “man” looked a rather “old forty-five”, for he was already going grey.“metonymy” 
 8. The delicatessen “owner” was a spry and “jolly fifty”.“metonymy”
 9. It was easier to assume a character without having to tell too many lies and you brought “a fresh eye and mind to the job”. “metonymy”
10. Some remarkable “pictures” in this room, gentlemen. A “Holbein”, “two Van Dycks” and if I am not mistaken, a “Velasquez”. I am interested in pictures.”“metonymy” 
11. ”You” have nobody to blame but yourself. The saddest “words of tongue or pen”. “metonymy”
12. For several days he took an hour after his work to make inquiry taking with him some “examples of his pen and inks”.“metonymy” 
13. There you are at your tricks again. The rest of them do “earn their bread”; you live on my charity. “metonymy”
14. I crossed a high toll bridge and negotiated a no man’s land and came to the place where “the Stars and Stripes” “stood” shoulder to shoulder with the “Union Jack.“metonymy” 
15. The praise was enthusiastic enough to have delighted any common writer who earns his “living by his pen”. “metonymy”
16. He made his “way through the perfume and conversation”.“metonymy” 
17. His mind was alert and people asked him to dinner not for old times’ sake, but because “he was worth his salt”. “metonymy”
18. Up the Square, from the corner of King Street, passed a woman in a new bonnet with pink strings, and a new blue dress that sloped at the shoulders and grew to a vast circumference at the hem. Through the silent sunlit solitude of the Square “this bonnet and this dress floated northwards in search of romance”. “metonymy”
19. Two men in uniforms were running heavily to the Administration building. As they ran, Christian saw them throw away their rifles. They were portly men who looked “like advertisements for Munich beer”, and running came hard to them. The first prisoner stopped and picked up one of the discarded rifles. He did not fire it, but carried it, as he chased the guards. He swung the rifle like a club, and “one of the beer advertisements went down“. “metonymy”


1. The book was entitled Murder at Milbury Manor and was a whodunit of the more abstruse type, in which “everything turns on whether a certain character”, by catching the ‘three-forty-three train at Hilbury” and “changing into the four-sixteen at Milbury”, “could have reached Silbury by five-twenty-seven”, which would have given him just time to disguise himself and be sticking knives into people “at Bilbury by six-thirty-eight”.“irony” 
 2. When the, “war broke” out she took down the signed “photograph of the Kaiser” and, with some solemnity, “hung it in the men-servants’ lavatory; it was her one combative action”. “irony”
 3. I had a plot, a scheme, a “little quiet piece of enjoyment” afoot, of which the very cream and essence was that this “old man and grandchild should be as poor as frozen rats”, and Mr. Brass revealed the whole story, making himself out to be rather a “saintlike holy character”.“irony” 
 4. The lift held two people and “rose slowly, groaning with diffidence”.“irony” 
 5. England has been in a “dreadful state for some weeks”. “Lord Coodle would go out. Sir Thomas Doo-dle wouldn’t come in, and there being nobody in Great Britain (to speak of) except Coodle and Doodle, there has been no Government”.“irony” 
 6. From her earliest infancy Gertrude was brought up by her aunt. Her “aunt had carefully instructed her to Christian principles”. She had “also taught her Mohammedanism, to make sure”.“irony”
 7. She’s a “charming middle-aged lady” with a “face like a bucket of mud” and “if she has washed her hair since” Coolidge’s second term, “I’ll eat my spare tire”, rim and all.“irony” 
 8. ”With all the expressiveness of a stone” Welsh stared at him another twenty seconds apparently “hoping to see him gag”. “irony”
 9. Well. It’s shaping up into a “lovely evening”, isn’t it? Great, he said.
And if I may say so, “you’re doing everything to make it harder”, you little sweet.“irony”
10. ”Mr. Vholes is a very respectable man”. He has not a large business, but he is a very respectable man. He is allowed, by the greater attorneys to be a most respectable man. He never misses a chance in his practice which is a mark of respectability, “he never takes any pleasure, which is another mark of respectability”, “he is reserved and serious which is another mark of respectability”. “His digestion is impaired which is highly respectable”. “irony”
11. Several months ago a magazine named Playboy which “concentrates editorially on girls, books, girls, art, girls, music, fashion, girls and girls”, “published an article about old-time science-fiction”.“irony”
12. ”Apart from splits” based on politics, racial, religious and ethnic backgrounds and specific personality differences, “we’re just one cohesive team”. “irony”
13. A local busybody, unable to contain her curiosity any longer, asked an expectant mother point-blank “whether she was going to have a baby”. Oh, goodness, “no”, the young woman said pleasantly. “I’m just carrying this for a friend”. “irony”
14. Sonny Grosso was a worrier “who looked” for and “frequently managed to find”, the dark side of most situations. “irony”
15. ”Bookcases covering one wall boasted a half-shelf of literature”. “irony”
16. I had been admitted “as a partner in the firm” of Andrews and Bishop, and throughout 1927 and 19281 “enriched myself and the firm” at the rate of perhaps forty dollars a month.“irony” 
17. Last time it was a “nice, simple, European-style” “war”. “irony”
18. He could walk and run, was full of exact knowledge about God, and ‘entertained no doubt concerning the special partiality of a minor deity called Jesus towards himself”. “irony”
19. But every Englishman is born with a certain miraculous power that makes him master of the world. “As the great champion of freedom and national independence he conquers and annexes half the world and calls it Colonization”. “irony”
20. ”All this blood and fire business” tonight was probably part of the graft to get the Socialists chucked out and leave “honest businessmen” safe to make their fortunes out of murder. “irony”
21. He spent two years “in prison”, making a number of “valuable contacts” among other “upstanding embezzlers”, frauds and confidence men whilst inside. “irony”


1. I was “scared to death” when he entered the room. “hyperbole”
 2. The girls were “dressed to kill”. “hyperbole”
 3. Newspapers are the organs of individual men who have jockeyed themselves to be party leaders, in countries where a new “party is born every hour” over a glass of beer in the nearest cafe. “hyperbole”
 4. I was “violently sympathetic”, as usual. “hyperbole”
 5. Four loudspeakers attached to the flagpole emitted a “shattering roar” of what Benjamin could hardly call music, as if it were played by a “collection of brass bands, a few hundred fire engines, a thousand blacksmiths’ hammers and the amplified reproduction of a force-twelve wind”. “hyperbole”
 6. The car which picked me up on that particular guilty evening was a @Cadillac limousine about seventy-three blocks long”. “hyperbole”
 7. Her family is one “aunt about a thousand years old”. “hyperbole”
 8. He didn’t appear like the same man; then he was “all milk and honey” — now he was “all starch and vinegar”. “hyperbole”
 9. She was a “giant of a woman”. Her bulging figure was encased in a green crepe dress and her feet overflowed in red shoes. She carried a “mammoth red pocketbook” that bulged throughout as if it were stuffed with rocks. “hyperbole”
10. She was very much upset by the catastrophe that had befallen the Bishops, but it was exciting, and she was “tickled to death” to have someone fresh to whom she could tell all about it. “hyperbole”
11. Babbitt’s preparations for leaving the office to its feeble self during the hour and a half of his lunch-period were somewhat “less elaborate than the plans for a general European War”. “hyperbole”
12. The little woman, for “she was of pocket size”, crossed her hands solemnly on her middle. “hyperbole”
13. We danced on the “handkerchief-big space” between the speakeasy tables. “hyperbole”
14. She wore a pink “hat, the size of a button”.“hyperbole”
15. She was a “sparrow of a woman”. “hyperbole”
16. And if either of us should lean toward the other, “even a fraction of an inch”, the balance would be upset. “hyperbole”
17. He smiled back, “breathing a memory of gin” at me. “hyperbole”
18. About “a very small man” in the Navy: this new “sailor stood five feet nothing in sea boots”.“hyperbole” 
19. She busted herself in her “midget kitchen”. “hyperbole”
20. The rain had thickened, “fish could have swum through the air”. “hyperbole”



1. He caught a ride home to the “crowded loneliness” of the barracks.“oxymoron” 
 2. Sprinting towards the elevator he felt amazed at his own “cowardly courage”. “oxymoron”
 3. They were a “bloody miserable” lot — the miserablest lot of men I ever saw. But they were good to me. “Bloody good”. “oxymoron”
 4. He behaved “pretty busily” to Jan. “oxymoron”
 5. Well might he perceive the hanging of her hair in fairest quantity in locks, some curled and some as if it were forgotten, with such a “careless care” and an art so hiding art that it seemed she would lay them for a pattern. “oxymoron”
 6. There were some bookcases of “superbly unreadable” books. “oxymoron”
 7. Absorbed as we were in the pleasures of travel — and I in my “modest pride” at being the only examinee to cause a commotion — we were over the old Bridge. “oxymoron”
 8. ”Heaven” must be the “hell” of a place. Nothing but repentant sinners up there, isn’t it? “oxymoron”
 9. Harriet turned back across the dim garden. The “lightless light” looked down from the night sky. “oxymoron”
10. Sara was a menace and a tonic, my “best enemy”; Rozzie was a disease, my “worst friend”. “oxymoron”
11. It was an “open secret” that Ray had been ripping his father-in-law off. “oxymoron”
12. A neon sign reads “Welcome to Reno — the “biggest little” town in the world.” “oxymoron”
13. Huck Finn and Holden Caulfield are “Good Bad” Boys of American literature.“oxymoron”
14. Haven’t we here the “young middle-aged” woman who cannot quite compete with the paid models in the fashion magazine but who yet catches our eye? “oxymoron”
15. Their “bitter-sweet” union did not last long. “oxymoron”
16. He was sure the whites could detect his “adoring hatred” of them. “oxymoron”
17. You have got two “beautiful bad” examples for parents. “oxymoron”
18. He opened up a wooden garage. The doors creaked. The garage was “full of nothing”. “oxymoron”
19. She was a “damned nice” woman, too. “oxymoron”
20. A very likeable young man with a “pleasantly ugly” face. “oxymoron”

1. You cheat, you no-good cheat — you tricked our son. Took our son with a “scheming trick”, “Miss Tomboy, Miss Sarcastic, Miss Sncerface.” “antonomasia”
 2. A stout middle-aged man, with enormous “owl-eyed spectacles”, was sitting on the edge of a great table. I turned to him.
Don’t ask me, said “Mr. Owl Eyes” washing his hands of the whole matter. “antonomasia”
 3. To attend major sports event most parents have arrived. A “Colonel Sidebotham” was standing next to Prendergast, firmly holding the tape with FINISH. Capital, said Mr. Prendergast, and dropping his end of the tape, he sauntered to the Colonel. I can see you are a fine judge of the race, sir. So was I once. So’s Grimes. A capital fellow, Grimes; a bounder, you know, but a capital fellow. Bounders can be capital fellows; don’t you agree. “Colonel Slidebottom”... I wish you’d stop pulling at my arm, Pennyfeather. “Colonel Shybottom” and I are just having a most interesting conversation. “antonomasia”
 4. I keep six “honest serving-men”
(They taught me all I know);
“Their names are What and Why and When
And How and Where and Who”.
I send them over land and sea,
I send them east and west;
But after they have worked for me
I give them all a rest.
I let them rest from nine till five,
For I am busy then,
As well as breakfast, lunch, and tea,
For they are hungry men.
But different folk have different views.
I know a person small -
She keeps ten million serving-men,
Who get no rest at all.
She sends ’em abroad on her own affairs,
From the second she opens her eyes -
“One million Hows, two million Wheres,
And seven million Whys.” “antonomasia”
 5. Her “mother” is perfectly “unbearable”. Never met such a “Gorgon”. I don’t really know what a Gorgon is like, but I am quite sure, that Lady Bracknell is one. In any case, she is a monster without being a myth.“antonomasia”
 6. Our secretary is “Esther D’Eath”. Her name is pronounced by vulgar relatives as Dearth, some of us pronounce it Deeth. “antonomasia”
 7. When “Omar P. Quill” died, his solicitors referred to him always as “O.P.Q.” Each reference to “O.P.Q.” made Roger think of his grandfather as the middle of the alphabet. “antonomasia”
 8. Your “fur” and his “Caddy” are a perfect “match.” I respect history: don’t you know that Detroit was founded by Sir Antoine de la Mothe”Cadillac”, French “fur trader”. “antonomasia”
 9. Now let me introduce you — that’s “Mr. What’s-his-name”, you remember him, don’t you? And over there in the corner, that’s the Major, and there’s “Mr. What-d’you-call-him”, and that’s an American. “antonomasia”
10. ”Cats” and canaries had added to the already stale house an entirely new dimension of defeat. As I stepped down, an evil-looking “Tom” slid by us into the house. “antonomasia”
11. Kate kept “him” because she knew he would do anything in the world if he were paid to do it or was afraid not to do it. She had “no illusions about him”. In her business “Joes” were necessary. “antonomasia”
12. In the moon-landing year what choice is there for “Mr. and Mrs. Average”-the programme against poverty or the ambitious NASA project? “antonomasia”
13. The next speaker was a “tall gloomy man”. “Sir Something Somebody”. “antonomasia”
14. We sat down at a table with two girls in yellow and three men, each one introduced to us as “Mr. Mumble”. “antonomasia”
15. She’s been in a bedroom with one of the young “Italians”, “Count Something”. “antonomasia”

